

# Serena Tomassetti

🛱 15th April 1989

Zürich, Switzerland

் L'Aquila, Italy

C-Permit

## **CONTACTS**

**&** +41 76 728 42 70

□ serenatomassetti001@gmail.com

serenatomassetti.com

in linkedin.com/in/serena-tomassetti

# **SKILLS**

HCI, User Research, Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, Information Architecture, UX Writings, Usability Test, Data-driven decisions.

#### **TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

Figma, Sketch, Abstract, Balsamiq, Creative Cloud, Zeplin, Google Analytics, Look Back, Mouseflow.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Italian: native

English: fluent (C1)

German: professional (B2)

#### **PASSIONATE ABOUT**

Design, art, photography, skiing,

hiking, traveling.

## REFERENCES

Naresh Shan, Head of Design at iptiQbySwissRe

naresh.shan@googlemail.com

#### SUMMARY

Resourceful User Experience Designer with broad practice in design and customer experience. I promote a user centered approach across companies. I am recognized for critical thinking, accuracy to details, self management . I am a curious person, an hungry reader and traveler, with a high interest in technology and innovation.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **UX Designer • IptiQ By SwissRe**

Zürich • Mar 2021 - Present • Contract

Conducted user research and user tests for B2B2C projects for our partner IKEA. Communicated the results with all the project's stakeholders (Confluence, slides, user flows, heat maps, journey maps, mock-ups, prototypes). Agile methods.

# **UX Designer • Muume AG**

Zürich · Dec 2020 - Feb 2021 · Contract

Designed digital interfaces for B2B and B2C softwares for commerce and multi-channel payment solutions. Conducted user research, communicated the results with stakeholders.

# **UX Designer • Visit Altopiano**

Rome (Remote) • Sep - Nov 2020 • Contract

Designed touristic mobile app for Visit Altopiano from research up to the implementation. Collaborated with stakeholders.

## **UX Designer • Bar Voce**

Rome (Remote) • Apr - Jun 2020 • Contract

Designed digital strategy for Bar Voce's safe restart during the Covid-19 pandemic. Collaborated with stakeholders.

#### **UX Designer • Freelance**

Zürich · Aug 2019 - Present

Planned and conducted user research for different freelance projects. Communicated the results with the stakeholders, developed product strategies, designed digital products. Provided high fidelity mock-ups, style guides, prototypes.

## Brand Ambassador · Lindt & Sprüngli

Zürich • Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

Identification of customer needs and behaviour. Sales and customer experience. Collaborated with marketing bridging observations and proposing solutions. Support on store layout, stock, and visual merchandising.

#### **Promoter • M.Prestige Promotions**

Zürich • Sep 2017 - Aug 2018

Identification of customer needs and behaviour. Target sales for YSL, Dior, Chanel and customer experience. Trained on customer psychology and behavior from Brand Managers.

#### Travel Designer • Ed è Subito Viaggi

Rome • Jan - Jul 2015

Designed tailored travel experiences, established long-term customer loyalty and returning customers. Identification of customer needs, customer experience and support.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **User Experience Nanodegree**

Udacity • 2020

Created an end-to-end digital user experience ready to be handed off for development.

- User research for qualitative and quantitative data Analysis and Synthesis of collected data
- Design Sprint Low and High fidelity wireframes and prototype Style guide and Design library
- Usability test and Iterations.

# **User Experience Bootcamp**

Interaction Design Foundation • 2019 - 2020

Designed a Project Management Web app through 1 to 1 mentorship sessions and guidance.

- User Research Design Sprint Sitemap Low and High fidelity wireframes and prototype
- Style guide and Design library.

## **Travel Experience Design**

Centro Turistico Studentesco - CTS, Italy • 2014

Lead the team for the design of a new travel itinerary in Brazil starting from the identification of a new travel concept until the prove of feasability.

• Market Research and Competitive Analysis • Travel Product ideation • Design of new itinerary • Prove of feasable implementation • Presentation of the project.

#### **Bachelor of Art**

**University of L'Aquila, Italy • 2008 - 2013**Cultural and Environmental Heritage.

## **Erasmus Exchange**

**University of Zagreb, Croatia • 2012 - 2013**Master's Thesis in History of Architecture.

#### **LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

- UX Management: Strategy and Tactics, Interaction Design Foundation, 2021.
- Conducting Usability Tests, Interaction Design Foundation, 2021
- Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner, IBM 2021
- Information Visualization: Getting dashboards right, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Gamification: Creating addictive user experiences, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Affordances: Designing intuitive user interfaces, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Accessibility: How to design for all, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Emotional Design: How to make products people will love, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Agile Software Development, University of Minnesota, 2020
- Human Computer Interaction- HCI, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- UI Design Patterns for succesful software, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20
- User Research Methods and Best Practices, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Mobile UX Design, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Design Thinking, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Fundamentals of Graphic Design, typography and storytelling, Californian University of Arts, 2019.
- Store Layout & Visual Merchandising, London University of Arts, 2018
- Travel Experience Design, CTS, 2014.